[Music]
you're listening to the AI native Dev
brought to you by
Tesla on today's episode we're going to
be talking about ai's role in testing
and joining me today is James Ward
developer Advocate at AWS at previously
Google and James is I just realized
actually I'm wearing my Java Champion
shirt as well James is also a Java
Champion a test containers champion and
you're currently a developer Advocate
AWS tell us a little bit about that
James yeah thanks Simon for having me so
this is super fun yeah so I'm I'm pretty
new into AWS I've been using it for a
very long time uh because I've had
servers uh in a Data Center and would
have to go in the middle of the night
and work on those servers and as soon as
AWS came out I was like oh thank God so
I've started using AWS a long time ago
but but yeah so I'm pretty new into AWS
and still learning a lot of things there
and and I'm a developer Advocate and
working on I don't know how do
Enterprise developers be more productive
using AWS and obviously with Java and
scholin cotland and my background get to
still use those languages and yeah so
back to the cloud after a couple years
as a product manager on the cotlin
language at Google so amazing exciting
change yeah welcome to the podcast James
it's it's a and we've known each other
for a fair amount of time from the Java
space as well so it's a pleasure to do
this this episode with you now one of
the one of the things that caught my eye
on should we call it x no let's not
let's on Twitter I still call it Twitter
just yeah let's let's call it Twitter
for reasonable denial denial of the
inevitable
future so one of the things that caught
my eye on Twitter was a tweet of yours
and I'm going to read this tweet out if
the AI can write the code iteratively
until it passes my tests why do I need
the actual code if it has bugs write
better tests future compilers will just
have all this integrated humans will
have to get good at writing the tests
which convey the business and operating
requirements now James I am well aware
that Twitter is one of these places that
has a lot of sense a lot of people
trolling uh a lot of people who have
many different opinions
serious on all of this was some of it
guessing to the Future some of it poking
fun at AI folks where do you sit on this
yeah I mean Twitter's Twitter's fun
because you can have these conversations
with people you don't know and who knows
where they're going to lead and all the
different perspectives that you see
along the way so yeah it's fun to to be
able to throw out a crazy idea and then
get some interesting responses and
that's what happened with that tweet was
I don't know I've been using these AI
tools more and trying to see how they
fit into the work that I do and the code
that I write and so one of the I think
we don't really know like how these
tools are going to be used in five 10
years and there's probably lots of
different ways that they'll be used but
one of the things that thought about is
the AIS are getting pretty good at
writing code for us why if the code that
it can write is just the right code why
do I even need to see the code why is
that even part of my code face and so
there after tweeting that this idea
popped into my head I'm like I think
I've heard about something like this
before and if you'll remember 4G
languages were this idea that you'd have
these like that you would I don't maybe
was like low code is the like 4gl
movement and so I was like somebody has
to have come up with what 5gl is and so
of course I went to Wikipedia and was
like was like Hey fifth generation
language and of course it was basically
describing what my tweet was about is
the AI is gonna you're gonna write your
tests or they in kind of more futuristic
languages you don't necessarily write
tests you write like proofs and so so
yeah so I was like oh like people have
obviously ever already thought about
this my my idea is not novel is always
so but one interesting thing of course
is the reaction that it gets and I think
it's interesting because we're in that
we're in that funny state with AI right
whereby A lot of people are using a lot
of very assisted tools today so it's
very interactive and it tends to be very
good at doing kind of like small jobs
and and and people are getting used to
that and enabling or or bringing in AI
into existing workflows in fact a great
example of that is I was chatting with
you earlier talking about AWS code
Whisperer which has now been rebranded
to AWS developer and that does a lot of
these kind of things right when we think
about
writing code ourselves it's there step
by step line by line helping us as an
assistant to to get us to The Next Step
which is here's the line of code I think
you wanted to write or here's the test
case that I think you want to create for
this the the Tweet however takes that to
it's extreme and there's a lot of people
who are still uh maybe a little bit
unsure of today's the the present
reality and I think you always find
people who want to truly believe in and
see the future of where this is going to
lead us and others that are very
skeptical about whether this is the true
path yeah that's for good reason we've
we've been through so many hype cycles
and I I have a funny story kind of
related to this there was a long time
ago I was at the Denver Java user group
and the presenter didn't show up and so
the organizer asked hey does anybody
have anything they can present on and
this this gray bearded man who I I
didn't know gets up and I got something
that I can talk about he's I'm gonna
tell you about something that's gonna
change the world and we were like oh
interesting he's like
XML none of us had even heard of XML at
the time and he's this is XML is GNA
completely change everything and then he
went on and talked about his crystal
ball gazing of all the ways that he
thought XML was going to change the
world and XML certainly did change the
world in many ways but looking back at
that the ways that it changed the world
were very different from what we thought
at the time for how it was going to
change the world and we went through all
the like soap stuff and all the Ws Splat
stuff and I don't know if you remember
all that but there was all these
attempts at like how is this how does
this actually get integrated into daily
work and getting our jobs done faster
and more efficiently and certainly XML
has changed many things and now we see
it in Json and other formats and Proto
Buffs and all sorts of stuff but yeah so
there was something very significant in
what XML was shifting but no one really
knew what that would be like 10 20 years
down the road and so I think we're at
the same point with AI we see AI being
used in all sorts of places we see the
people that are resistant to to the
change and I think that it's just we
don't know like how the what this is
going to look like in in 10 years and
there's people that are like oh
developers are going to be no longer
needed and there's people who are on the
other side of the spectrum and so yeah
it's that wild time where there's this
huge hypee cycle lots of change lots of
crystal ball gazing and if anyone
actually knew like going back to the XML
thing like no one actually knew like
what the future would look like and in
part because it's iterative right and
like we try things we make some changes
based on those things and then we try
new things and so it's just you can't
imagine how all the iterations are going
to play out so I think that's exactly
where we're at with AI yeah absolutely
so what I'd love to do is actually go
through somewh we've grouped some of the
replies to this tweet and we'd love to
go through them do we before we do that
do we need to expand on this idea a
little bit or do you think let's let's
let's talk a little bit about it I think
yeah what you in fact whyn't you rather
than me describe your Tweet what why
don't you take us through it yeah so I
think today what some developers are
doing is they start writing some code
and then maybe you're using a code
assistant to fill in the boiler plate
almost or the in bits and that's great
that's okay that's nice that a lot of
times I can spend less time thinking
about about the code that I need to
write because the AI has been able to
come up with something just based on
what I started typing and I think that's
a good step but for me I'm wondering why
does that code actually need to exist in
a human readable form if the AI can
actually get it right so if the AI if
all that I need is some form of way to
express add what I'm trying to get to
then why does the code need to be
readable maybe it does for debugging
maybe it does for other reasons but if
we could get to a point with the AIS
where the code has been sufficiently or
the specification of the code what it
needs to do has been sufficiently
defined then why does there need to
actually be human readable code and I
think there's a few challenging aspects
to that one I mentioned both of them in
the the Tweet there I'll expand on them
one is it this requires our
specifications to be sufficient to know
that the functionality is what I would
need and there's all sorts of
complexities to doing that because a lot
of times the code that we actually are
working on has some kind of
intangible aspects to it that need to be
covered especially on the operational
side so on the operational side you may
know that this particular function is
going to be called a million times in
100 milliseconds or whatever you you may
have some ideas around the performance
characteristics that you need this
function to have and so you as a
developer generally would optimize that
particular function for those
operational production requirements but
why don't why aren't those production
requirements specified in our tests and
I think generally our testing Frameworks
don't get into the operational
requirements of a system the security
requirements of a a system and part of
what I'm saying would need to happen is
we would need to be able to specify not
just the functional requirements of
something but also the kind of
production characteristics that we need
to get to like the in a test would have
to say I expect this thing to return in
0.5 milliseconds or something like that
and I'd expect it to use this much
memory or like we generally just do that
those requirements on the development
side not on the testing side but we
would need to then be able to move those
requirements to our specification and
not just have that be something that we
iterated to the production requirements
that that we thought were the right ones
yeah and we covered a lot there because
then the specification becomes quite
broad then right because if you look at
the specification you mentioned things
like the behavior of the app um which I
guess can be defined in a couple of ways
one through the tests the the assertions
that the that the behavior needs to meet
the other could just be the the behavior
you want to see through function
functionality description so I need this
calculator to add these two numbers
together and then a test or an assertion
that follows to say if I provide two and
two I need it to give me the answer for
and so forth then the nonfunctional part
of that as well that you mentioned the
security the performance maybe
architecture style requirements you
might have yeah it's quite a big
document right yeah yeah and it it's the
way that I look at it is I love type
systems and so you as the developer
probably should be specifying the the
actual types of the thing and so you're
going to write your class definitions
out and then you're going to write out
the interface that that is going to be
used and then what I'm proposing is that
you've written your classes you've
written your interface and you've
written your tests and then the actual
implementation is what could be filled
in by the AI because I still do want to
have my types I do want to have the
interface the function definitions to
interact with that that those objects
and then I want to have the tests that
validate the functionality and then the
production aspects to it so you
mentioned interfaces classes types and
and
objects how deep into the
implementation the or or rather even the
ecosystem we're assuming here probably
more like a a Java or a skyar light
language with some of the verbiage that
we're using does that matter could I is
it possible just to say look this is
what I want use the best language I that
you think is going to work for this
rather than a language that I am most
familiar with because if I'm not going
to read it as much as other tools does
it need to be more familiar with me yeah
it's a good question I do think that we
have seen many different kind of testing
dsls and so there's a huge variety of
ways that you can describe your tests
and yeah there it's going to be
interesting to see how that space
evolves there's a cucumber The Groovy
one and anyways people have used all
sorts of different like dsls for
describing their tests I have some
personal preferences in this direction
where I've moved to the place where I
actually like to write my tests as just
regular code no special dsls no no
assertion libraries that have all these
fancy things on them I like to just do
assert true and then that means that my
code in my test actually is normal code
it's not some weird d cell and so maybe
that's part of this is like the way that
I have written my test isn't some
bespoke thing only for testing it's just
the normal code that I write elsewhere
yeah so I don't know if that would be a
kind of requirement for this AI thing
actually working but maybe we see new
test testing specification languages
evolved as part of this and I think
that's the 5gl description is actually
saying that there will be new languages
that evolve in this space that are more
targeted at this kind of view yeah it'll
be interesting to see how that happens I
think you you could theoretically do
this in any language but I like to have
there's a few things that I like to have
in this space that I think are useful
one is a good type system so you can
specify your types because I think that
that is part of your specification and
then as part of when some when somebody
becomes a consumer of your your API than
having the types and the functions
defined in a very specific way is is
helpful so you know I don't know how
this would work in like Dynamic
languages yeah absolutely one of the one
of the themes of answers that people
replied and people did reply in droves
to your Tweet was that tests aren't good
enough one person said they only capture
a fraction of what code is capable of
and some things are very hard to test
another person said no someone has to
still maintain the thing um and work out
why if it's behaving in an unexpected
way why this is the case another person
says not sure that tests will be enough
want to as you mentioned just now want
to be able to specify types constraints
and things like that as well so are
people like conflating a little bit too
much of the today versus The Vision here
James or is there a point here yeah I I
think it's some good feedback and I
think that that yeah generally
our tests today are insufficient to be
able to do this and but my my
perspective is that maybe our tests
should be more sufficient to cover these
sorts of things maybe our tests are not
enough like for me tests the usefulness
of tests is that it makes me as a
developer more productive in the moment
that I'm writing the code and then also
in the future when things are changing
to verify that I don't have regression
and that sorts of thing so I don't yeah
for me it's like if you see mature
projects what generally they do is if
somebody finds a bug then you go and
write the test first to validate that
that the bug does exist and you can
reproduce it and then you come out with
the fix and then verify that your test
pass and that to me is just a good way
to work because then you verify that one
you've actually fixed the bug and two
that you're not going to break that
functionality in the future because then
your CI is going to break and so for
yeah for me a big part of is our test
should be sufficient to handle all this
and and one of the things that you
mentioned there at the at the very top
was maybe we're not in the right place
today with the the quantity of tests or
the quality of tests that we have if we
look at how AI could help us there today
this is a wonderful Vision or an very
interesting Vision that that one day we
could quite easily see us getting to but
in the interim there are still things
like awq developer as a great example
tools that can help us actually build
the test Suite that we should have today
we'll do actually a nice little demo and
talk through a little bit of that in the
episode literally straight after which
will be which will be being published on
the same day as this one but yeah talk
us through what developers in an ideal
world today what the workflow should be
to use AI in the testing space yeah I
think some people are using AIS to take
some code and then say write the test
for me and I I think maybe if you have
existing functionality that's that is a
viable way to go like you you haven't
written a test yet but you've written
the functionality I think the AIS are
getting pretty good at coming up with
the test for your existing functionality
I'm not like a strict tdd person but I
do tend to write test first or I I write
and I guess there's different levels of
it I write my types I write my function
signatures and then if maybe if the
logic that I need to build is complex
some level of complexity then I do
actually start writing the test because
I don't really understand what I need to
build and the functionality that needs
to be validated until I've described it
in a test so I'm not like a totally and
sometimes there's going back and forth
between okay I'm going to write some
functionality I'm going to modify my
test and so it's a little iterative for
me in different ways depending on the
functionality that I'm writing and
sometimes I don't write test at all
because the logic is either really hard
to test or very test doesn't add a whole
lot of value and yeah I think there's
this whole spectrum of what where and
when and how you write your tests but
for me in most of the way that I write
code I've not done the thing where I
highlight some existing functionality
and say now write the test but certainly
there are people who worked differently
in that that approach could have value
so so I think there's there there's that
use case where people want to use it to
help them write their tests um the ways
that I've been using uh the AI assistant
stuff is when I'm diving into areas that
I don't understand um new I've been
working with new languages I've been
working with rust for example or or yeah
just domains I'm not as familiar with
the typical way that I would work is I
would go to Google and ask a question
and then I would open like 300 tabs with
all the stack Overflow answers all the
blogs that I can find all the Reddit
Pages whatever and then I'd have to read
through all those things and start to
get an understanding of I'm like
manually assembling this knowledge
structure in my head and now what I
generally do is instead of doing that
process I just go into my case Q
developer and I just start asking
questions and I think that the benefit
of that is that it's already done the
300 tab thing and assembled its
knowledge and then I can start to cater
the response and and start to ask
follow-up questions and so for me that's
been the one of the primary use cases is
just the asking questions and I know
people use chat GPT and I think co-pilot
and or you can use Claud from anthropic
there's lots of different ways that that
have these knowledge bases essentially
you can go start asking questions too
yeah so I think that's the first way
that I've gained a lot of value from the
AIS I'll pause there and see if you have
anything broke on yeah know and I I hear
that a lot actually people in fact I saw
a really interesting video the other day
where someone I think they were using
Claude or something like that and it was
actually around a podcast guest and what
they said they did was they would upload
entire books as well as previous
episodes or videos that they' done and
push scripts into there and it would
create you know large amounts of flow
and questions and things like that and
that's what AI is amazing at right it's
about make me much much more effective
by learning all this information in a
second or or using all this context in a
second and then give me that summary of
what is useful and what is most
important for me to know now and that
efficiency boost is simply quite
incredible today A lot of times it's
pretty accurate on those kinds of
answers and but there are times that you
get the hallucinations and
I think that one of the challenging
things is how to identify when something
feels off and so there's I think it for
people that are very experienced they
get a spidey sense tingly sense oh that
doesn't feel quite right that doesn't
align with how I understand the world
and so I think that's something that
still is a gap is for people that aren't
experienced enough to be able to get
that like spidey sense on something like
they can go down some pretty serious
rabbit holes and then find out way too
late that oh this was I was completely
misled in this direction and so I don't
know how maybe the models just keep it
getting better and eventually fewer
hallucinations or is there a way to get
the community to help check those
answers or help be like H this doesn't
feel right and run it through a human
that has a a brain and experience and
can help identify the the things that
may be wrong and yeah I think that's
still an open problem I was talking to
someone just this week actually on the
podcast who talked a little bit about
the confidence level because because LMS
tend not to want to say no they they
want to provide an answer somewhere even
if an answer doesn't exist and that's
very often where hallucinations can
arise um and sometimes knowing when to
say look I I'm not sure about this or I
I have the confidence issue with the
answer I'm giving you so just be aware
that this is an area that needs to be
checked as well because I think a lot of
the time exactly like you say there are
some people that will say yeah I I can
see that this is a some people that will
happily accept it as the truth because
they're just not as experienced in that
space so almost having the LM come back
to us and say look I'm just confident in
this or I'm not confident in this you
need some additional information or
additional input or maybe human input
there to to go get someone to to talk
exactly and I've seen some people
customize their prompts and so when they
start a new prompt session they'll say
something like if you don't know say you
don't know and I don't know if that's
Universal across to all of the llms and
models but I have seen that used on some
models and then the llm if it doesn't
have a high confidence will actually say
I don't know and then I I think one of
the things that's currently missing from
this experience is I haven't seen maybe
it exists but I haven't seen I haven't
seen an llm Ask follow-up questions yeah
and so as a developer there's a lot of
different spaces and how many times do
we say it depends and I guess what I
haven't seen the LMS do is be like it
depends tell me more about this and
that's where I think there's definitely
some room for improvement is instead of
just giving an answer have the the llm
actually start to understand the context
and the related things better before it
starts spitting out an answer and so
maybe more of a like we would do as
humans is oh tell me more about that I
want to understand that piece more
before I tell you what the answer is
yeah yeah it requires quite a different
dynamic in terms of the chat UI versus
versus kind of like a single prompt but
yeah 100% I think I I really agree with
that another response category was just
AI plane isn't ready to do this kind of
thing and I know it's accelerating at a
ridiculous Pace now and I absolutely
agree it's not ready today but yeah they
went on to say have you used co-pilot or
chat GPT or Claude or whatever they
still get a lot
wrong so here's something that is is
beginning to happen which I think is
really fascinating the space is this
first came up I was on a work group
where there was a bunch of companies
that were looking at how do we convert
Java code to cotlin code and one of the
ideas in that space is oh maybe the LMS
can do it for us but the challenge is
that that as you're saying sometimes the
LMS are going to get it wrong and so
what can we do about that and so there's
been some experiments in that space
where what you do is you have a process
around the llm that takes some Java code
converts it to cotlin code and then it
runs your compiler runs your build and
if that generate new generated code
creates a compile error then you feed
that compiler back into the LM and say I
got this air and then you tell it to try
again or modify the code to fix the air
and and then you could iterate through
this Loop maybe you could even change
models or change model parameters or
something like that to iterate to
something that actually compiles and
then maybe your next step is to then add
your actual test for that thing into the
loop as well and so then you start to to
create this feedback cycle with the llm
to then iterate to something that
actually works all good in theory I
tried this on a rust project so I was
working rust I'm not a rust expert and I
was getting a compiler warning in on
this piece of rust code and so I fed
that into an llm and said hey fix this
code for me and so it gave me back some
code I was like sweet great and so I put
that code in and then it's then I get a
compiler instead of just a warning i'
now the code that it was given me it was
now a compiler and so then I gave the
compiler code to the LM and said fix
this compiler for me and it gave me back
the code with the warning and so then I
was just in this recursive Loop of it it
couldn't resolve through iteration to
something that actually worked but was
that just a context problem where it
didn't have enough context from the
previous iterations where it learned
okay I can't do that cuz I tried that
and that's what happened maybe I need to
think outside the box that's almost
where not hallucination necessarily but
thinking out the box to try and work out
a different solution could actually
that's a good point yeah the fuzziness
of these and potentially throwing other
models at it as well this model maybe
isn't going to be able to iterate to a
solution but let me try a different
model and see yeah so I think you're
right like this iterative feedback loop
with multiple LM
potentially could get us much closer to
a working solution but like none of this
infrastructure exists around this yet no
one has no one that I know of is has
written tools that can like actually
integrate this iterative feedback loop
into a normal development process and so
so yeah I think we're still at the
beginning of this kind of Journey for
how we can use these tools to to iterate
more effectively to Working
Solutions yeah the the next category was
and and I think there's there's a couple
like this but talking about eventually
yes that will be the case but in the
meantime we need a human in the loop
still and I think there's two pieces
around this one is still in terms of the
where the technology is but if we think
about we just talked about AI not
potentially being ready just yet what
about us as humans not being ready
because technology can change bang
overnight and and it's quick however
humans they take time to adjust their
workflows and time to do development in
a different way are we the going to be
the slowest part of this this puzzle in
terms of changing the way we develop and
getting used to it and getting
comfortable with trusting what what
what's coming out of it yeah I think
we're in a moment of
co-evolution with these tools and yeah
the humans are changing the AIS are
changing and we're both co-evolving and
and that's back to the beginning where
we talked about not really knowing where
this all goes is both sides are
iteratively moving forward but they're
also entangled and moving forward
together in a away and yeah I think like
we as humans are going to have to change
how we think about things how we
approach problems how we use the tools
but then obviously the tools are also
changing and so yeah it's for
now one of the most important things
when using these tools is what one of my
my co-workers says is is you still have
to use your brain what the tools are
doing they're assisting you they're
helping you but you still need to use
your brain and be able to look at some
code and be like that code is not what I
need and and whether it's code or
whatever the llm is coming up for you
writing documentation like Java dos
incredibly useful tool that the llms can
do for us now but you still need to read
your Java and be like is this actually
correct and so yeah I think it's this
pairing between the tools and our brains
based on all the experience that we have
and the business problem that we are
understanding and trying to solve yeah
and and that actually came up a couple
of times as well in just from the point
of view of the abstraction and saying
this is just another abstraction to
where we are now this person this
individual didn't imagine a big
difference between how we work now to
later so ask computer to do something
run it verify and repeat and iterate
through that which yeah to some extent
is true it obviously changes the changes
what we are physically doing
a machine and and potentially let's talk
a little bit about what you consider the
dev role to be in this kind of like
future space you were previously talking
about that it's the human that still
needs that brain to actually be able to
whether it's design or whether it's
create the app in the way that they want
to achieve something is the developer
just that one level abstracted higher
and focusing on on the app that that's
slightly high level ignoring the lines
of code or how is done things are done
and focusing more on the what
yeah that was an interesting comment
where somebody is like so we essentially
just the future is that developers are
business analysts and are the ones that
can take the the business requirements
and translate them into a specification
is that what you're proposing and I
don't know if that's what the future
looks like I I don't know if I would be
very super stoked on that because I like
solving problems and getting into to
code and like figuring out the right
ways to model things and test things and
the like mechanics of a lot of this
stuff not so I don't get super excited
about understanding users and their
needs so let's talk about that because I
think that's a really important piece of
as to where development goes because
developers aren't developers just
because let's go into this space because
there's a ton of money in it they do it
because they love problem solving and
they enjoy coding so in this new world
what is the where's the fun where what's
the thing that is going to get a
developer to have that amazing moment
where they solve something is that still
going to
exist I I sure hope so I would be bummed
out if if the AI took the fun Parts out
of the job because yeah I think
hopefully where this goes is that the AI
takes the not fun parts and does those
for me and then I get to focus on the
fun Parts but I don't know what that
actually looks like for would I enjoy my
job if all that I was doing was writing
a test and the types and the interface
would that be fun for me I don't know if
it would that creative piece by seeing
an application being built up by writing
spec versus actually writing the code
because you are still creating but you
could argue as well exactly like you
said if you can get the AI to do those
things that you either don't like doing
or takes time and isn't actually that
part of the creation everything from
tests as well but documentation those
kind of things that keep everything up
to the standard which often when we look
in open source spaces and other areas
your mileage varies across many
different libraries and packages right
there's that aspect as well going
further into the future some people say
do you know what this is great but you
didn't go far enough there's something
beyond what you're saying which is
talking about developers or what we
would label as a developer in the future
they're just going to write test specs
rather than Implement
um and people will use AI for writing
tests as well so instead of treating AI
as a solution effectively just to build
code you'd treat it as a companion that
says I'm going to write some tests I'm
going to write some code it does it all
for me and my hands are clean it it
broadens the number of people that can
be that developer as well yeah where
does it
stop yeah I think we've seen so many so
many I don't know attempts but some of
them successful around low code or no
code and they're I think it's a wide
space And so there's going to be I'm
sure places that need developers who can
write code and debug code and get into
the Gory details of things and figure
out the hard problems and then just like
we have with low code and no code
there's going to be this widening of who
can actually be a developer who can
create things and an example that my
co-author podcast co-host Bruce eckel
likes to talk about is that we've got a
bookstore in in our little town we live
in here in crb Colorado and the software
that exists to manage a bookstore is
terrible because who is motivated to
build a team of 20 developers to build
good bookstore software right like it
just it doesn't make sense to for that
space to be solved because it's too
expensive to get to a good solution and
there's not not enough benefit to people
actually investing in that and so we
have a problem that that there are many
domains in our world that could be
better solved through software and yet
there's not enough
Financial motivation there people have
to spend many years learning how to
build systems to be able to solve those
problems and if we can W significantly
widen the net for who can actually solve
these problems like that is amazing and
could get our friend Arvin who runs the
bookstore good bookstore software that
he currently doesn't have because there
just isn't the
economic incentives for that to exist
and so I think great let's widen the
spectrum of who can solve many of the
problems around the world with software
I think that's a great thing but I don't
foresee there is the future is that only
people that don't know how to code but
know how to use AI tools are the only
ones that exist I don't I think it'll
just continue to be a spectrum of we
solve many different problems in the
space of software and and there's there
it's a very big tent with room for a lot
of people and a lot of different tools
and a lot of different skill sets and a
lot of different experiences so that's
my crystal ball take on is I don't think
developers are going away and being
replaced by AIS anytime soon but
certainly there will be developers that
use these tools to hopefully enable us
to be more productive and focus on the
fun Parts yeah sounds great sounds great
James this has been wonderful and yeah
next up actually we're going to we're
going to get a little bit more Hands-On
we're going to screen share and actually
actually see some see some of C in
action and talk a little bit about how
AI tools can help us help us actually
write better tests and write more tests
as we develop code James for the time
being thank you so much it was a really
great cheat that was a fun chat thank
you thanks for tuning in join us next
time on the AI native Dev brought to you
by Tesla
oh